<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://pixiotix.com</id>
    <title>Pixiotix • Posts by &#34;business&#34; tag</title>
    <link href="https://pixiotix.com" />
    <updated>2021-03-16T22:16:40.000Z</updated>
    <category term="Pixiotix" />
    <category term="Announcements" />
    <category term="Software Engineering" />
    <category term="Leadership" />
    <category term="Innovation" />
    <category term="Machine Learning" />
    <category term="Computer Vision" />
    <category term="History" />
    <category term="Business" />
    <entry>
        <id>https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/03/17/Creative-Leaps/</id>
        <title>Creative Leaps</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/03/17/Creative-Leaps/"/>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, ideas flow and sometimes they don’t. When working on a difficult problem, it’s really important to ensure you actually get the chance to work on it. Turn off notifications and other distractions and really think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going to another room &amp;amp; thinking on paper can help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Better yet, go for a walk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk to a colleague/peer - even if they can’t offer advice, just talking the problem through will often help shake a solution out from hiding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can’t force a creative leap. So if you’re still at a loose end, take a break, do something else &amp;amp; come back later or the following day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, your subconscious will deliver!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
        <category term="Pixiotix" />
        <category term="Innovation" />
        <category term="Business" />
        <updated>2021-03-16T22:16:40.000Z</updated>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/03/05/Let-the-fires-burn/</id>
        <title>Let the fires burn</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/03/05/Let-the-fires-burn/"/>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was thinking back on my days in engineering management at a particular very successful scaleup and recalling a bunch of times when we had issues, knew we had them, but we didn’t slow down to address them - we kept moving forward. Our customers knew about them and were telling us in no uncertain terms how unhappy they were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I considered just how successful we were, and whether that was &lt;em&gt;despite&lt;/em&gt; our handling of such issues or &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recalled an episode of Masters Of Scale:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you spend all of your time fighting fires, you may miss critical opportunities to build your business. You’ll be all reaction, and no action. But if you let fires go on too long, you’ll get burned. Deciding which fires you let burn, and how long you let them burn for, can make the difference between success and failure.&lt;br&gt;“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the customer always right? Or should you focus on success and worry about them later?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the episode, or really, the whole podcast for more detail &amp;amp; wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
        <category term="Pixiotix" />
        <category term="Innovation" />
        <category term="Business" />
        <updated>2021-03-05T03:27:37.000Z</updated>
    </entry>
</feed>
