<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://pixiotix.com</id>
    <title>Pixiotix • Posts by &#34;leadership&#34; tag</title>
    <link href="https://pixiotix.com" />
    <updated>2021-03-02T00:49:28.000Z</updated>
    <category term="Pixiotix" />
    <category term="Software Engineering" />
    <category term="Announcements" />
    <category term="Leadership" />
    <category term="Innovation" />
    <category term="Machine Learning" />
    <category term="Computer Vision" />
    <category term="History" />
    <category term="Business" />
    <entry>
        <id>https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/03/02/building-quality-products/</id>
        <title>Building quality products</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/03/02/building-quality-products/"/>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;How do you deliver &lt;em&gt;quality&lt;/em&gt; software products? Lots of automated testing? Go all in with TDD? Build a comprehensive manual test procedure? Invest in pair programming? Wait for your customers to find problems and fight the fires as they pop up?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to focus on a particular testing technique and assume quality delivery. Find bugs, fix bugs, ship software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But quality is about much more than that. Quality software comes from teams who care about quality as much as it comes from processes that seek to assure quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quality isn’t just about lack of bugs. It’s about how your system makes your customers feel - stability, security, consistency, usability, availability, design are all key parts of that experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to consider all quality across the whole system on a spectrum - which aspects of quality are non-negotiable in your product? Which are important enough to hold a release? Which can be released, but need to be fixed later? What types of issues do you just not care about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Define quality requirements and processes based on the overall priorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decide what quality means for your product, customers and team and have a plan to deliver.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
        <category term="Pixiotix" />
        <category term="Software Engineering" />
        <category term="Leadership" />
        <updated>2021-03-02T00:49:28.000Z</updated>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/01/27/31917185.when-a-measure-becomes-a-target/</id>
        <title>When a measure becomes a target...</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/01/27/31917185.when-a-measure-becomes-a-target/"/>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The saying “When a measure becomes a target, it ceases to be a good measure” applies very well to software development. If you’re trying to measure output / quality in software development using any simple measure you’re doing it wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Measuring lines of code? Expect verbose code...&lt;br&gt;Measuring tickets closed? Expect smaller tickets…&lt;br&gt;Measuring features completed? Expect a drop in quality...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pushing harder on these metrics when the going gets tough is only going to lead to developers gaming the metric, consciously or unconsciously.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The golden rule?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Build a team you can trust... and trust them.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
        <category term="Pixiotix" />
        <category term="Software Engineering" />
        <category term="Leadership" />
        <updated>2021-01-26T18:15:20.926Z</updated>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/01/21/31728180.hiring-engineers-stop-chasing-unicorns/</id>
        <title>Hiring Engineers - stop chasing unicorns</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/01/21/31728180.hiring-engineers-stop-chasing-unicorns/"/>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having trouble finding Software Engineers who are experts with years of experience in the exact technology you need? Well I’ll let you in on a secret - you need to stop looking for unicorns…&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Software languages, tools and systems move so fast that if an engineer isn’t continually learning, they’re falling behind. But great engineers aren’t just trying to keep up - they’re driven to experiment and learn. They’re always looking for ways to make their projects more efficient - whether that’s by tweaking their working environment, automating mundane tasks or learning whole new languages.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;An engineer with three languages and two web frameworks under their belt is going to have no problem getting up to speed on some missing experience if they’re sufficiently motivated.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Look for evidence of passion, learning and experimentation and use this to help your hiring decisions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;🦄 🌈&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
        <category term="Pixiotix" />
        <category term="Leadership" />
        <updated>2021-01-20T16:28:40.802Z</updated>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/01/20/31695977.remote-the-future-of-work/</id>
        <title>Remote - the future of work?</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/01/20/31695977.remote-the-future-of-work/"/>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I, along with so many other professionals suddenly started working from home last year, I thought it would be awesome. And it certainly had its advantages - no commute, less interruptions, more flexibility to exercise &amp;amp; spend family time. Many tech folk rejoiced and declared that this was the way we should all work, all the time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But work-at-home is no panacea. Many people simply don’t have the space / separation to do long term focussed work at home. Many have kids, family and house-mates around. Internet access varies wildly across cities and suburbs. Bad ergonomics can have a massive impact on people’s health when they are subjected to them full time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is also considerably harder to collaborate effectively remotely. Even with instant messaging, teleconferencing, virtual whiteboards etc, the ease of collaboration that can be obtained standing around a whiteboard in a meeting cannot be matched.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m about to take my business out of the small space I have carved out at home and full time into a co-working space. I’m looking forward to the change of scene, the separation from family, the tea room, and yes, even talking to other occupants of the space!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even the short commute is appealing - a little bookend to the working day.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Long term, I’d love to see companies experimenting with hybrid office/remote working setup. Where “remote” could mean home / paid co-work / or a satellite office. This could be a killer combination that balances flexibility &amp;amp; lifestyle with employee health and in-person collaboration which is so important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also published on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/remote-future-work-daniel-moore-/&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
        <category term="Pixiotix" />
        <category term="Leadership" />
        <updated>2021-01-19T17:17:46.561Z</updated>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/01/17/31599270.communication-is-key/</id>
        <title>Communication is key</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/01/17/31599270.communication-is-key/"/>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Strong collaboration requires strong communication. Building a culture of strong, open communication is critical in the success of teams.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good communication is clear &amp;amp; concise - it gets to the point and stays on the point.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good communication is correct and consistent - it’s fine to not have all the answers, or be confident about something. Giving a solid answer may require some research and it’s likely everyone will benefit from it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Encourage participation in discussions, and ensure contributions are heard and considered.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
        <category term="Pixiotix" />
        <category term="Leadership" />
        <updated>2021-01-16T16:07:36.765Z</updated>
    </entry>
</feed>
