<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Pixiotix • Posts by &#34;innovation&#34; tag</title>
        <link>https://pixiotix.com</link>
        <description></description>
        <language>en</language>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 09:16:40 +1100</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 09:16:40 +1100</lastBuildDate>
        <category>Pixiotix</category>
        <category>Software Engineering</category>
        <category>Announcements</category>
        <category>Leadership</category>
        <category>Innovation</category>
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        <category>Computer Vision</category>
        <category>History</category>
        <category>Business</category>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/03/17/Creative-Leaps/</guid>
            <title>Creative Leaps</title>
            <link>https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/03/17/Creative-Leaps/</link>
            <category>Pixiotix</category>
            <category>Innovation</category>
            <category>Business</category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 09:16:40 +1100</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;p&gt;Sometimes, ideas flow and sometimes they don’t. When working on a difficult problem, it’s really important to ensure you actually get the chance to work on it. Turn off notifications and other distractions and really think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going to another room &amp;amp; thinking on paper can help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Better yet, go for a walk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk to a colleague/peer - even if they can’t offer advice, just talking the problem through will often help shake a solution out from hiding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can’t force a creative leap. So if you’re still at a loose end, take a break, do something else &amp;amp; come back later or the following day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, your subconscious will deliver!&lt;/p&gt;
 ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/03/05/Let-the-fires-burn/</guid>
            <title>Let the fires burn</title>
            <link>https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/03/05/Let-the-fires-burn/</link>
            <category>Pixiotix</category>
            <category>Innovation</category>
            <category>Business</category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 14:27:37 +1100</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;p&gt;I was thinking back on my days in engineering management at a particular very successful scaleup and recalling a bunch of times when we had issues, knew we had them, but we didn’t slow down to address them - we kept moving forward. Our customers knew about them and were telling us in no uncertain terms how unhappy they were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I considered just how successful we were, and whether that was &lt;em&gt;despite&lt;/em&gt; our handling of such issues or &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recalled an episode of Masters Of Scale:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you spend all of your time fighting fires, you may miss critical opportunities to build your business. You’ll be all reaction, and no action. But if you let fires go on too long, you’ll get burned. Deciding which fires you let burn, and how long you let them burn for, can make the difference between success and failure.&lt;br&gt;“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the customer always right? Or should you focus on success and worry about them later?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the episode, or really, the whole podcast for more detail &amp;amp; wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;
 ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/03/04/The-Sunk-Cost-Fallacy/</guid>
            <title>The Sunk Cost Fallacy</title>
            <link>https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/03/04/The-Sunk-Cost-Fallacy/</link>
            <category>Pixiotix</category>
            <category>Software Engineering</category>
            <category>Innovation</category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 13:28:52 +1100</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;p&gt;It happens to the best of us. You’ve worked super hard, put in the hours, built something that should be awesome, but it’s just not working out. Being the dedicated individual you are, you plough more time into it. You’ve expended so much energy, that you can’t help but continue. Time to think about the Sunk Cost Fallacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should you continue down a path? Try a new approach? Abandon and try something new?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sunk Cost Fallacy tells us that only your current options really matter. Time, energy and money already invested in something has already been spent - it can’t be recovered - it’s a Sunk Cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at your options now, look at their costs going forward, and try to put the past aside. Make a decision, and go for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could you do with some help figuring out where your development is at? Looking for some advice and inspiration? Pixiotix provides independent technical consulting &amp;amp; advice for companies working on innovative software &amp;amp; hardware systems. Check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://pixiotix.com/&#34;&gt;https://pixiotix.com&lt;/a&gt; and get in touch to find out more.&lt;/p&gt;
 ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/02/22/32797937.starting-out-in-r-and-d/</guid>
            <title>Starting out in R&amp;D</title>
            <link>https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/02/22/32797937.starting-out-in-r-and-d/</link>
            <category>Pixiotix</category>
            <category>Innovation</category>
            <category>History</category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 07:43:54 +1100</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;p&gt;Upon leaving University, I joined &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/company/csiro/&#34;&gt;CSIRO&lt;/a&gt; and was thrown straight in the deep-end as the solo developer of the system software for the RoadCrack road-survey vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The prototype vehicle was capable of imaging the road, processing and classifying cracks down to 1 mm resolution at 105 kmph.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The software interfaced with custom FPGA based image acquisition hardware, distributing the image data from industrial line-scan cameras via high speed frame grabbers and a network of 5+ Digital Alpha computers which performed the processing. Data was reported to a front-end control user interface in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Image processing code developed elsewhere in CSIRO extracted cracking and classified each image. Development predated contemporary machine learning algorithms and relied on classical computer vision techniques.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The opportunity to work on the RoadCrack project and the support of the crew at CSIRO was instrumental in kicking off my ongoing career in innovative, R&amp;amp;D driven companies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More details on RoadCrack at https://csiropedia.csiro.au/roadcrack-1999/ and check out a promo video at https://csiropedia.csiro.au/automated-pavement-crack-detection-and-classification-1994/&lt;/p&gt;
 ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/02/19/32702669.automated-asset-inspection-with-ml/</guid>
            <title>Automated asset inspection with ML</title>
            <link>https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/02/19/32702669.automated-asset-inspection-with-ml/</link>
            <category>Pixiotix</category>
            <category>Innovation</category>
            <category>Machine Learning</category>
            <category>Computer Vision</category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 02:56:06 +1100</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;p&gt;I tuned in for a particularly interesting presentation as part of Smart Cities Summit 2021 yesterday. Some amazing work being done by Moreton Bay Regional Council and Retina Visions on automated visual asset inspection. They are leveraging their existing garbage collection vehicles to acquire video footage of the road and roadside during their rounds, and processing that video to identify all kinds of maintenance issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From road defects including cracking to curbside rubbish to overhanging trees - all detected automatically and fed directly into the council asset management system and used to dispatch maintenance crews.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also noted a great use of edge AI - to mitigate privacy issues, both faces and license plates are detected on the acquisition device and blurred as the footage is acquired. The redacted footage is then sent back to the cloud for the gruntier processing work of detecting and classifying the defect types. In this way it’s possible to leverage the huge processing power in the cloud whilst ensuring that sensitive data never leaves the truck.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s a really inspiring example of a council embracing new technology to reduce costs and improve services for their community.&lt;/p&gt;
 ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/02/01/32072277.whats-your-ip/</guid>
            <title>What&#39;s your IP?</title>
            <link>https://pixiotix.com/blog/2021/02/01/32072277.whats-your-ip/</link>
            <category>Pixiotix</category>
            <category>Innovation</category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 03:48:48 +1100</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;p&gt;When it comes down to it, there’s a lot of commonality between SaaS products. Signup, login, user management, dashboards, integrations. There’s a myriad of ways you can access / buy / build this functionality and there’s little technical risk involved in getting it working. A key question early on is: “What’s your intellectual property”?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your IP is key because it’s what differentiates your product from others - having strong IP is key to not being overtaken by a bigger, better funded competitor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But developing your IP will be harder, slower and carry considerably more technical risk than developing the rest of the product. Finding engineers who can build what you need will be harder too.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ask yourself early on what’s unique about your product? What’s the fundamental technical core to what you’re trying to do? How can you increase your understanding &amp;amp; decrease the technical and resourcing risks so you’re not surprised down the track?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Look after your IP and your IP will look after you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pixiotix specialises in consulting for founders developing innovative software / hardware products with critical IP. Check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://pixiotix.com&#34;&gt;https://pixiotix.com&lt;/a&gt; and get in touch to find out more.&lt;/p&gt;
 ]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
